# Florin LIPAN

#### About

I'm a Ruby developer with a strong devops background and leadership experience. I've taken various lead roles in the past and like to engage with all sides of product development. I know my way around AWS, Ansible, Kubernetes, Docker and Linux. I can speak SQL to your database and GraphQL to your clients. I have a personal interest in languages like Crystal and Rust. I know a thing or two about HTML, CSS, Javascript and what makes a good UI/UX. I value clean, simple, boring code and try to be pragmatic while keeping my standards high. I can write concise, well structured documentation. I enjoy learning, teaching and being self-organized.

_		
$\nu_{\rho}$	こくい しょうしょうしょう	חחו

Email <u>florinlipan@gmail.com</u>

GitHub / Projects <u>https://github.com/lipanski</u>

Website / Blog <a href="https://lipanski.com">https://lipanski.com</a>
Place of residence Berlin, Germany

Languages Solid English, German, Romanian. Some French.

#### Experience

## May 2020 - Present Chatterbug / Senior Software Developer (Ruby on Rails)

A hands-on experience building a feature-rich language learning and video streaming platform together with the founders of GitHub. I improved the website performance by 40%, nurtured the Rails monolith and designed complex GraphQL APIs. I guided other developers in their daily work through pairing, code reviews, planning and patience. I introduced Turbo Streams, Stimulus and GraphQL Subscriptions to the stack, significantly reducing our development time. I learned a lot about developing a complex product with a very small team.

#### Jul. 2018 - Apr. 2020 Blacklane / Head of Engineering (Platform)

A partially hands-on management role. I'm providing high-level technical guidance to the Blacklane Platform teams (Infrastructure, Geolocation, Payment, Back-office, Salesforce, Internal APIs, ~15 engineers), trying to empower developers whenever I can, but getting my hands dirty when I'm needed. I'm handling recruiting and interviews, providing feedback in 1:1 sessions and mentoring team members. I'm trying to keep engineering standards high, apps running smoothly and people engaged and happy.

## Sep. 2014 - Jun. 2018 Blacklane / Lead Backend Developer (Ruby)

A merry mix of backend development, devops, software architecture and management tasks. I helped tame the Rails monolith, designed and partially developed the new Booking API and developed various (micro)services in Sinatra or Rack using MySQL, Postgres, Redis, Sidekiq, Puma and others. I got deeper into ops, got familiar with a wide range of AWS services from VPCs to CloudFormation and built our infrastructure around Ansible. Over the course of the last year, we shifted towards Kubernetes and Docker. I introduced new processes, handled technical interviews and performed product management tasks. I improved the performance of our systems and lived to see some beefy infrastructure migration Sundays.

Feb. 2014 - Aug. 2014 Blacklane / Backend Developer (Ruby)

Nov. 2012 - Jan. 2014 Axonic / Full Stack Developer (Ruby on Rails)

I developed a fairly complex product from scratch, while being the only developer on the project. Working closely with the CEO, I learned not just full stack Ruby on Rails but also what's important to customers, how to plan and how to build a product.

Dec. 2010 - Aug. 2012 Axonic / Full Stack Developer (PHP5, Symfony)

Apr. 2009 - Jul. 2010 Pi Technologies / Developer (PHP, CMS, Javascript)

# Education

2010 - 2011	Karlsruhe Institute of Technology M. Sc. Informatics (discontinued)
2006 - 2010	Technical University of Cluj-Napoca B. Sc. Informatics, 240 ECTS Points, 9.5/10